Carver, Maryann mss., ca. 1955-1988 LMC 2774
Lilly Library
Carver, Maryann mss.
ca. 1955-1988
Lilly Library
Carver, Maryann.
LMC 2774
1 Box 1 standard
Carver, Maryann mss., ca. 1955-1988, consist primarily of correspondence, photos, and memorabilia between Maryann Carver and her first husband, writer Raymond Carver.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Maryann Carver married Raymond Carver in June 1957, when she was sixteen and he was nineteen. They were married for twenty-five years, and had two children, Christi and Vance.
Considered one of the major writers of the late 20th century, Carver is best known for his short stories with subject matter focusing on blue-collar experiences and aspects of his own life. His first published collection of short stories Will You Please Be Quiet, Please? (1976) was shortlisted for the National Book Award and his 1988 short story collection published just before his death, Where I'm Calling From, was nominated for both a Pulitzer Prize and a National Book Critics Circle Award.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the follow series: I. Correspondence; II. Academic Awards; III. Literary Works; IV. Miscellaneous; V. Photographs.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondents include: Bob Adelman, Saul Bellow, Christi Carver, Vance Carver, John Gardner, Curt Johnson, Gordon Lish.
Academic Awards include Carver's graduation pamphlet from Humboldt State College and various honorary degrees. Literary Works include a Syracuse University literary magazine edited by Carver and a copy of his short story A Small, Good Thing. Miscellaneous items include flyers for readings and tributes, a copy of the short story Neighbors first published in Esquire magazine in 1975, and a copy of the undated short story The Pearl. Photographs include an undated portrait of Carver and photographs of Carver's early life.
Related Material
Related manuscripts: Lish mss.; Carver, V. mss.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2012
Authors, American--20th century--Correspondence; Carver, Maryann --Correspondence.; Carver, Raymond, 1938-1988.; Carver, Raymond, 1938-1988 --Correspondence; Adelman, Bob --Correspondence.; Bellow, Saul --Correspondence.; Lish, Gordon --Correspondence.
- Correpondence
  - Adelman, Bob, 1977-1991 (Box 2)
  - Carver, Maryann (To Raymond Carver), 1983-1988 (Box 1)
  - Carver, Raymond (To Maryann Carver) (Box 1)
    - 1956 (Box 1)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 1)
    - 1980-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1986 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Carver, Raymond (To his daughter Christi and his sister in law, Amy Burke Unger), 1987; undated (Box 2)
  - Carver, Raymond (To his son Vance), 1979-1988; undated (Box 2)
  - Carver, Vance (To Ray Carver), 1981-1982; undated (Box 2)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1964-2008 (Box 2)
    - Gardner, John, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Thurston, Jarvis, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Pearce, Richard, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Publisher Acceptance Correspondence, 1961-1970 (Box 2)
    - Between Worlds: The International Magazine of Creativity, 1961-1963 (Box 2)
    - Russell, Karen M, 1962-1965 (Box 2)
    - Gardner, John, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Marks, Jeff, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Rippy, Mayhew Frances, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Thompson, Charles, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Bourne, Louis M, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Gustafson, Richard, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Tyler, Robert L, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Baily, Carl L, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - Glauber, Robert H, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Hiatt, Ben, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Curt, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - Csikszentmihalyi, Mihaly, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Candelaria, Frederick, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Abt, Diane, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Robinson, Charles, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Bartholomew, Alick, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Ravenel, Shannon, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Amidon, Barbara E, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Morgan, Robert, Undated (Box 2)
    - Brown, Michael, Undated (Box 2)
  - Publisher Acceptance Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
    - Luke, Hugh, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Yiell (?), John, 1968 (Box 2)
    - McCrindle, Joseph, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, Carl L, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Hitilar, George, 1968 (Box 2)
    - The Colorado Quarterly, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Patterson, Rebecca, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Hicks, Jack, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Ursenbach, Maureen, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Burns, James F, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Keitel, Frances, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Hogins, James Burl, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Freund, Betsy, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Curt, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Publisher Acceptance Correspondence, 1971-1982 (Box 2)
    - Carroll, Paul, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Freund, Betsy, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Tucker, Martin, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Rackstraw, Loree, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Tudish, Cathie, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Brooks, Patricia, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Nyberg, Ben M, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Coggeshall, Rosanne, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Hayman, David, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Schaeffer, Maureen, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Griffith, E.V, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Carlson, Maurice I, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Crome, Nick, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Patterson, Rebecca, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Milton, John, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Abrahams, William, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Harris, Dorothy McKittrick, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Arteseros, Sally, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
    - Henderson, Bill, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Gerson, Ed, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Berkowitz, Bernice, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Reed, Kit, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Gildner, Gary, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Memmott, Roger L, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Lish, Gordon, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Henderson, Bill, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Green, Roy, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Cady, Barbara, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Between Worlds: The International Magazine of Creativity, 1961-1963 (Box 2)
    - Russell, Karen M, 1962-1965 (Box 2)
    - Gardner, John, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Marks, Jeff, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Rippy, Mayhew Frances, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Thompson, Charles, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Bourne, Louis M, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Gustafson, Richard, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Tyler, Robert L, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Baily, Carl L, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - Glauber, Robert H, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Hiatt, Ben, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Curt, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - Csikszentmihalyi, Mihaly, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Candelaria, Frederick, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Abt, Diane, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Robinson, Charles, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Bartholomew, Alick, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Ravenel, Shannon, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Amidon, Barbara E, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Morgan, Robert, Undated (Box 2)
    - Brown, Michael, Undated (Box 2)
    - Luke, Hugh, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Yiell (?), John, 1968 (Box 2)
    - McCrindle, Joseph, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, Carl L, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Hitilar, George, 1968 (Box 2)
    - The Colorado Quarterly, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Patterson, Rebecca, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Hicks, Jack, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Ursenbach, Maureen, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Burns, James F, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Keitel, Frances, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Hogins, James Burl, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Freund, Betsy, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Curt, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Carroll, Paul, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Freund, Betsy, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Tucker, Martin, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Rackstraw, Loree, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Tudish, Cathie, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Brooks, Patricia, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Nyberg, Ben M, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Coggeshall, Rosanne, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Hayman, David, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Schaeffer, Maureen, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Griffith, E.V, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Carlson, Maurice I, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Crome, Nick, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Patterson, Rebecca, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Milton, John, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Abrahams, William, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Harris, Dorothy McKittrick, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Arteseros, Sally, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
    - Henderson, Bill, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Gerson, Ed, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Berkowitz, Bernice, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Reed, Kit, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Gildner, Gary, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Memmott, Roger L, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Lish, Gordon, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Henderson, Bill, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Green, Roy, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Cady, Barbara, 1982 (Box 2)
- Academic Awards
  - Humboldt State College Commencement booklet, 1963 (Box 2)
  - National Endowment Grant, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Brandeis University Citation award, 1988 (Box 2)
  - University of Hartford commencement pamphlet, Doctor of Letters, 1988; (2 copies) (Box 2)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters Doctor of Letters, 1988 (Box 2)
- Literary Works
  - Syracuse Poems and Stories selected by Carver and foreword written by Carver, 1980 (Box 2)
  - A Small, Good Thing, 1981 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Flyer for reading with Ann Beattie, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets for tribute on the 30th anniversary of Will You Please Be Quiet, Please? created by the PEN/Faulkner Foundation, 2006; (4 copies) (Box 2)
  - Copy of Neighbors short story featured in Esquire magazine, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Copy of The Pearl short story, undated (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Portrait of Raymond Carver, undated (Box 2)
  - Various family photos, undated (Box 2)